how come do you restring the rocket
right
oh you want the orange string don't you
yeah you want me to restrain it for you
but then that's a good question how
often do you receive the racket so how
many times per week do you play
three three times per week yeah
okay i would say you string it once
every two months if you play three times
a week so i'm overdue then
yeah you are yeah you want me you want
me to put on the orange string
how about like green i don't have green
strings orange would be fun
orange you want orange it's going to
match your grip yeah
all right anna listen i have a surprise
for you today what is it okay we're
going to try something new
here take a look take a look on the
court take a look here
i have something for you are we
traveling look at that thing oh that's
this oversized luggage
it's a ball machine we're gonna do a
ball machine training today are you
excited
yeah i've never done it all right let's
try it out okay
i'm gonna turn this thing on let's see
what happens okay
pretty self-explanatory it's gonna shoot
the ball you start off with four hands
uh the good thing about
you playing on the ball machine is that
i can look at your technique
close up all right being
at already it's gonna come it's warming
up oh wait it's it's set too low hold on
hold on anna i'm gonna set it on full
blast okay
there we go anna come on on your toes
one bounce rule here we go come on
at all what do you mean not even
come on anna come on
up and down with the racket back up
you're too close
give yourself more space i'll turn it
down a little bit a little bit too
long it's too long the ball okay let me
show you here watch
first of all don't be scared of the ball
and just be
patient be calm cool as a cucumber
and see some of these balls are dead
they're not gonna bounce as high
but see just be calm you see the ball
machine has respect
and now it's not shooting it as far you
see this anna
all right timeout time out time out
i'm going to turn it down but in general
you see the forehand you're panicking
when you panic
technique goes back to this it's like
sloppy the arm is just flailing around
in the air
look ball comes you go here this all you
got to do is this
as soon as you you know it's going to be
a forehand so you can be like this the
whole time
you don't even need a ready position you
just go here and you're waiting in this
position
then once you're ready to swing you
initiate your stroke you take it back
okay i'm gonna go over there i'm gonna
turn it down a couple notches and we'll
try again okay
come closer come close
there you go perfect yes
anna yes bring the racket to the side
go again you're dropping it too soon
wait longer on top time out first of all
let me move these balls behind you
and then we got a little bit of a
problem on the forehand okay
you're dropping the racket a little bit
too quick so you're going here which is
good
but then you're dropping it over here
come look the racket needs to go back
first and then it needs to drop
look here back first and then you drop
it in the back don't drop it here in the
front
right because then you go back to the
old swing okay
oh let's try it again
don't drop it too early stay on top
better and just bring it around all the
way bring the racquet around the body
finish
strong beautiful forehand
look at these forehands anna well
how good was that where is he asleep
ball machine is asleep it might be out
of balls
so let me pick let me get a basket i'm
going to pick up with the basket
yeah okay i'll be right back with you
okay come with me
see it's fun the ball machine right well
it's fun right yeah
so here's what i want you to do i know i
want you to really work on the first
step on the forehand
being towards the side of the body with
the racquet right here
waiting here and then you initiate the
stroke close to the bounce
by taking the racquet back so you just
wait here to the side
initiate close to the bounds and then
finish once you come over on this side
you can see my forehand a little bit
better
so you're going to see how i'm waiting
here initiate and finish so right away i
go to the side and i just wait here like
this
yeah this is all i'm doing and now it
bounces and i start
initiating the stroke by taking the
racket back which
uh follows shortly after the take back
is the
torso rotation you see here i'm waiting
here like a back
torso rotation
there it is you take my place come on
do the same thing
go again there were you two sideways on
that one
go again it's all right you'll find your
rhythm
late put the racquet to the side right
away
pause it real quick um see what you're
doing
is the ball comes and you're waiting
here too long the racket is facing this
way
what i need you to do is just wait on
this side remember we talked about this
like very early on when we learned the
forehand
you need to set up in a sideways
position find the ball on the side of
the position
from here the first move is to actually
take the racket back
and then when the racket starts to drop
you can start thinking about opening up
you do a pretty good job with that
but sometimes when the ball overwhelms
you come stay right here
when it imagines the ball the ball gets
behind you and now you're in big trouble
yeah you can't really hit a ball from
back there yeah so the timing is crucial
you need to set up
your feet in the right place you need to
prepare the stroke early in order to
time it well all right try a few more
come on wait to the side don't even
worry about that you know it's a
forehand
there you go strings towards me strings
towards me
there it is beautiful forehand you see
you drop it too early drop it in the
back
much better on it that's beautiful
a little bit late on that one you hit it
too far behind
late again
oh wow look at that whip nice
didn't like that one come again wow look
at that clean forehand ana
look at this this is crazy good again
i like the footwork anna
don't drop it too early
stay up with the racquet up and then
down
up and down better up
then down come again
absolutely perfect that forehand
too late a little bit late
get that left arm towards me a little
bit longer i don't like the left hand
pointing forward get it to me to me
left arm to me with the racquet yes like
this left
left arm and racket i didn't turn it off
it's pretty stuck but look
when you turn don't go like this because
this opens you up a little too early
wait here when the racquet goes back and
starts to drop now your left hand can
get out of the way but don't have the
left arm here
it doesn't put your body yeah it doesn't
put your body on the balance it's a
little bit off balance this way
because your body weight will when you
start adding a little bit more power to
your forehead you're going to start
leaning towards
this side when the arm is here it
doesn't work you're off balance i often
tell juniors to imagine pushing someone
on this side with both hands
there you go that's it there it is
you're pushing someone here look
racket goes back left hand gets out of
the way and you whip that thing you
understand the concept
i think so okay go ahead and push me
push me come on there you go that's your
forehand go again
push me there you go
that's it yeah yes push someone here
push
and then you get out of the way once
that person's out of the way you're
ready to hit
come on
the anticipation is killer right i can't
handle it
not front side on the side with the
racquet there you go
that's it push it
perfect
a little bit too far behind perfect best
forehand of your life
nice workout all right now i'm gonna
flip the ball machine around we'll do
some backhands
your favorite don't know the two in the
back end let me just give you a couple
of
quick tips okay so you can see yeah no
you can't see on that side you go over
there
all right if you say so look racket
needs to be here a little bit above the
grip
say second right here now i don't know
what you're doing this is not smart but
i listen
now i missed the ball you got me all
confused you need to take the racquet
back
and have the racket head slightly above
the grip okay
when you finish look at the look at the
both elbows up look at my right elbow
you see and i'm finishing all the way
hey this is kind of fun anna
i don't know if i'm gonna let you play
i'm gonna continue is that okay
i'm just kidding here one more oh just
do it like me
you see that finish it over i take my
spot
come on whoa that's a beautiful backhand
on a back with the racquet immediately
good backing up
rack it up and back immediately
go again on the back
immediately there you go perfect
it's okay it's a good miss adjust your
positioning a little bit don't let the
ball play you
don't let the ball play you okay
okay i like it anna i like it anna nice
go again nice one
wow what a backhand and here match point
give me one more
rip it one more time
good footwork one more time come on last
one
there is no more up on me it's good
enough i think it's out of balls
but a couple of takeaways that is going
to be super super important
that i was able to see even more
convincingly when i was
next to you is the preparation must be
good if you want to have a chance
on both of your shots so let me recap on
your forehand
when you see it as a forehand you can
immediately go into this position
and set up and just pushing somebody now
the backhand is going to be a little bit
different you can't go like this on the
backhand
so you're going to go so imagine me
hitting this way i'm going to go before
you go
to the backhand like you're pushing
somebody yeah and then with the left
hand can you like
clarify for me yeah because i understand
it's kind of like
yeah see but i want to know like what is
this
the only doing in the biomechanics the
only thing that you need to think about
is getting the left hand out of the way
let me can you give me the ball right
there i'm going to show you a drill
and we've done this one before so this
is the drill that i do with like
entry level players you go right here
you can see so this is the perfect
explanation of what the left hand does
on the forehand
i'm going to stretch it out over here
i'm going to push somebody now i'm going
to let the ball go as soon as i let it
go
i'm going to start pulling it away now
it doesn't necessarily rotate the
shoulders when you pull the
the arm away but you need to start
rotating the shoulders
as you're pulling your left arm away
that is the main purpose of the left arm
and then as it's going around the body
it needs to tuck in so you have space
for the racket to finish on this side
okay so basically the
left hand can help the shoulders to
rotate
so take a look here i'm going to drop
this ball watch my left hand it's going
to get out of the way as soon as i drop
the ball
and it's helping me rotate the shoulders
so it's not like using its leverage nah
not like that just
it's got nothing so it doesn't bother
the key on the forehand is that
here i'll show you over here this side
the key on the forehead is that when you
hit the forward phase you know what the
forward phase is when the butt cap is
pointing towards the other side
when you hit this phase on the forehand
your chest needs to be open
before the well it's kind of already all
right so the way we're going to do that
is by starting the rotation early and
where we're going to start it
in the racket drop because we do have a
loop so when the racket drops we start
opening so that when we hit this we
already open
and now we continue going forward we get
the dominant shoulder in front of
contact
we continue to rotate and finish like
this does that make sense
the left hand just retracts the left
hand gets out of the way
but it helps to rotate the shoulders
sometimes like tennis players do this
and they lift it
even they lift it in the air i never
seen that never seen anyone go in the
air
there's one guy that was going like this
this guy called goldbes
but they all do it a little bit
different everybody has a little
different style some have a little bit
more straight here
this will be a little bit more bent here
but it's all the same biomechanics
the key on the forehand is that you
don't want to be sideways when the
racket goes forward if you're here
you're guaranteed to make contact too
far back because you're going to
simultaneously go forward with the
racket
and rotate and you'll make contact with
the dominant shoulder behind so what
needs to happen is
this side needs to get out of the way in
the racket drop so that when you hit
this you're already open and you're
guaranteed to make contact further in
front
makes sense because your chest and your
racket kind of
parallel to the ball right it can be it
has to be at least parallel
on the pros this shoulder gets actually
a head they make contact here
but you want to be at least parallel you
don't want to be behind now you're going
to have
problems because the body is blocking
the racket here and you'll probably
steer the ball forward
yeah okay so
again we're talking about the
preparation that is key
so as soon as you see a forehand you go
like this push somebody yeah
on the backhand it's different because
you don't want to go
like this like push someone on the
backhand you need to take the racquet
back this way the hands need to go
behind the body now the key on the
two-handed backhand is that to keep the
racket head a little bit higher
okay
the handle so you're going to go this
back and comes you're going right here
here you can wait like this and set up
like this
and now wait distribution is between
like you just don't worry about it it's
not going to be on your back foot it's
not going to be completely on your front
foot it's going to be somewhere in
between
but don't worry about that naturally
you're going to be evenly distributed
with your feet
and now the stroke gets initiated when
the racket starts to drop
that's the initial initiation of the
two-handed backhand so you can wait
in the back with the racquet like this
can i look at
the stroke without the ball okay from
your front
like what you want me to hit towards you
yeah like hit that way
yes all right so here here's the
backhand yeah why don't i turn on the
ball machine you just watch me there
okay here let me turn it on i'll hit a
couple more backhands here hold on i
can't use my watch
um i hope that there's a little balls
left in there
oh yeah it got stuck remember should i
like move it
i'll do it you stay yeah oh wait no
maybe it's coming
the key is the finish now as i'm
finishing i'm hitting myself in the back
with the racket yeah i always do
i have actually that's fantastic
that's fantastic you see but the setup
is key watch
i see the ball i'm here and i finish it
so let's do some let's let's rally a
couple and see how we do okay okay all
right
again
come on go again rack your head a little
bit higher in the back
a little bit higher in the back don't
forget to move
nice job it's okay
come again
good good anna
up up up
game set match anna look um
it's possible that when you're switching
between like real tennis and ball
machine it's so different
that you might lose your rhythm each
time so when you haven't played with a
ball machine in a while the first like
five minutes
you're like oh the ball's coming weird
you have no timing no rhythm and then
the same thing if you're playing a ball
machine then you play against
a person the first five minutes probably
gonna be a little bit weird
but then you get used to it so don't
worry about that part that's just
you naturally get used to the incoming
ball the more you see it oh i have so
much fun
all partners are different that's what i
mean blue partner we have today that's
an excellent point
every partner is different that's the
challenging part about tennis
you know but the good news is that the
stuff that we're working on those are
the fundamentals
you have to have those regardless of who
you play against
all right we're getting close on it
we're getting very close yeah okay
good work today thank you nice did you
have fun with the ball machine or
yeah it was really interesting it's like
artificial intelligence kind of thing
you can borrow it if you want oh you
want it should it
you can you can you can have it you can
take it today if you want
oh i'll take it tomorrow we're gonna
take it in your car today
maybe you can teach me how to use it
because i wouldn't know
take it seriously yeah and practice with
it yeah um i'm going to explain to you
how to use it now
and just stick it in your trunk yeah and
use it whenever you want
sure i'll take it back from you if i
need it but i don't need it for a while
you sure i'll do it yeah i need you
playing as much as possible
but i play with people so you got people
you got clinic
you got wall and you got it you're done
all right whatever
but i will go we scratch the clinic but
you got people
ball machine wall yeah and you and me i
have no excuse that's right